Guide to the Gimon Conference on French Political Economy
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gimon Conference on French Political Economy
2004 Apr 17-19
SC1084
Stanford University. Libraries.
0.23 Linear feet 18 optical discs (CD)
Audio CDs from the conference, along with the printed program.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
In April 2004, the Stanford University Libraries and the France-Stanford Center for Interdisciplinary Studies, with the generous support of the Flora Family Foundation, sponsored an international conference, The Gimon Conference on French Political economy. This event brought together over 20 scholars from the US, France, and Great Britain, for 3 days of presentations and debates.
Papers focused on topics and primary sources held in the Stanford University Libraries' Gustave Gimon Collection of French Political Economy, including: the scope of royal or government power, economic theory and international trade, religious theory and tolerance, colonial policies and slavery, utopian socialism and social engineering. The ideas of the Physiocrats, and of thinkers such as Montesquieu, Rousseau, Turgot, Proudhon, Fourier, and Saint-Simon were among the topics discussed.
The Gimon conference coincided with the publication of A vast and useful art: the Gustave Gimon Collection on French Political Economy, edited by Mary Jane Parrine. Stanford University Libraries, 2004, a book containing the catalogue of the Gimon Collection of French Political Economy, as well as detailed thematic essays on its "highlights" and five essays by leading scholars.
Description of the Collection
Audio CDs from the conference, along with the printed program.
Access Terms
Gimon Conference on French Political Economy, 1650-1848 (16-19 April 2004: Stanford University); France--Economic conditions.; France--Politics and government.; France--Social life and customs.; Gustave Gimon Collection of French Political Economy.; Social history--France.
Collection Contents
- Audio recordings
  - Opening Remarks1, 2004 Apr 17; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 1U)
  - Opening Remarks2, 2004 Apr 17; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 1U)
  - philosophie economique, 2004 Apr 17; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 2U)
  - Panel 1, part 1, 2004 Apr 17; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 3U)
  - Panel 1, part 2, 2004 Apr 17; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 4U)
  - Panel 2, part 1, 2004 Apr 17; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 5U)
  - Panel 2, part 2, 2004 Apr 17; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 6U)
  - Panel 2, part 3, 2004 Apr 17; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 7U)
  - Panel 3, part 1, 2004 Apr 18; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 8U)
  - Panel 3, part 2, 2004 Apr 18; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 9U)
  - Panel 4, part 1, 2004 Apr 18; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 10U)
  - Panel 4, part 2, 2004 Apr 18; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 11U)
  - Panel 5, part 1, 2004 Apr 18; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 12U)
  - Panel 5, part 2, 2004 Apr 18; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 13U)
  - Panel 6, part 1, 2004 Apr 19; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 14U)
  - Panel 6, part 2, 2004 Apr 19; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 15U)
  - Panel 6, part 3, 2004 Apr 19; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 16U)
  - Panel 7, part 1, 2004 Apr 19; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 17U)
  - Panel 7, part 2, 2004 Apr 19; 1 computer file(s) (WAV) (Box 18U)